I'm going to walk you through an example of a method with a different
異なるインプットの数を持ったメソッドの例を
number of input parameters.
見ていきたいと思います。
I started by creating a new app from the project wizard in Android Studio, so
Android Studioのプロジェクトウィザードを 使って新しいアプリを作り始めました。
this is completely unrelated to the Just Java app.
なので、Just Javeアプリとは関係ありません。
I added this method in the main activity.
main.activityにそのメソッドを加えました。
It's called createWeatherMessage.
creatWeatherMessageというものです。
There's no input parameters, and the return value is a string.
インプットパラメータはありません。 出力は文字列です。
This method is supposed to create a new message that specifies the city name and
市名と気温を表すメッセージを
the temperature.
作るメソッドです。
You can think of a method as being a template of instructions.
メソッドは、この練習ののテンプレートとして 見ることができます。
So I can make temperature be an input parameter.
なので、気温をインプットパラメータにすることができます。
And it's a number, so I'm going to say, int temperature.
数字なので、int temperatureとします。
And then I can use this right here.
これをここで使うことができます。
So, this is a string literal, and
これは列定数で、
then it's concatenated with the temperature integer.
気温に連結されています。
And then it's concatenated with another string that says degrees Fahrenheit.
そしてdegree Fahrenheitというもう一つの 文字列と連結されています。
So now the message can be customized based on the temperature because it's
メッセージはインプットなので、気温に応じて
an input parameter.
カスタマイズすることができます。
Oh yeah, I forgot to mention this earlier, but in the onCreate method of
言うのを忘れていましたが、activityが作られる時に呼ばれる
the main activity, which is called when the activity gets created,
main activityのonCreateというメソッドで、
I can call the createWeatherMessage.
createWeatherMessageを呼ぶことができます。
Before I passed in no arguments, but now we have one required parameter.
以前はインプットはありませんでしたが、 今度は一つパラメータがあります。
So I'm going to pass in 77 for the temperature.
７７を渡してみます。
Now that makes the error go away, and this method call is correct.
エラーが消えて、このメソッドコールは正しくなりました。
The other thing I should modify is this comment on the method.
もう一つはメソッドのコメントを変えることです。
I'm going to add a blank line, and
一行空けて、
then I'll start to describe the input parameter which is temperature here.
気温であるインプットパラメータを説明を入れます。
I'm going to type @param temperature, and
@param temperatureと記入して、
then I can add a description saying that this is the temperature of the city.
これは市の気温だという説明書きを加えます。
Sometimes the parameter names are a little hard to understand, so
パラメータの名前が分かりにくい時があるので、
that's why the description is useful.
説明書きはとても便利です。
Other times if your method is public then other people will be able
そして、メソッドがパブリックであれば、 他の人も
to call this method, and
このメソッドを呼ぶことができます。
they might not know what are the instructions inside this method.
メソッドの中の指令がどんなものかは分からないかもしれません。
So reading this java doc and
なので、java docでパラメータんお説明を読むのは
the description of the parameters is really useful to them.
とても便利なんです。
I mentioned earlier that a method is like a template.
さっきメソッドはテンプレートだといいました。
So, what if we want to change the city so that it's not always San Francisco?
サンフランシスコではなく、他の市を入れたい場合は どうすればよいでしょうか。
I can make city be an input parameter.
市をパラメータにすればいいですよね。
So I can just add a comma here.
ここにコンマを加えて、
And since city name is text I'm going to make it a string data type.
市市名はテキストなので、文字列のタイプを使います。
Then I can delete San Francisco and replace it with a variable city name.
サンフランシスコを消して、cityNameという変数を使います。
And remember to add a space before and after here as well.
ここの前後にスペースを加えるのを忘れないでください。
Cool, so now this method can create a message
これで、市名と温度をカスタマイズできる
that's customizable to a certain city and temperature.
メソッドが出来上がりました。
I also remembered to modify the java doc so
java docの説明を変えて、
that it has this extra parameter and description for a city name.
もう一つパラメータがあるということと、 cityNameという説明を入れておきました。
Since I changed the method signature, now I have an error up here.
メソッドのシグナニチャを変えたので、エラーが発生しています。
The method no longer works with just one argument.
１つのインプットではなく、
I need to pass in two arguments.
２つのインプットを渡さなければいけません。
So I add a comma and then pass in San Francisco string.
コンマをいれて、SanFrancisco文字列を入れます。
Now the error goes away.
これでエラーが消えました。
So when I call createWeatherMessage(77, it's going to be value of temperature,
createWeatherMessage(77を呼ぶと、 これは気温になります。
and San Francisco will be the value of city name.
サンフランシスコは市名ですね。
And it will create the proper string here.
ここで適切な文字列を作ります。
Now we're going to go back to the calculate price method,
つぎに、calculatePriceメソッドに戻って、
and we're going to modify the method signature so
メソッドシグニチャを変えて、
that it has a different number of input parameters.
異なるインプット数を持つようにします。
We're going to define it with zero input parameters, one input parameter,
パラメータが０、１、そして２というように
and lastly, try it with two input parameters.
作っていきます。
You'll see how changing the method signature here to have a different
メソッドシグニチャを変えてインプット数を変えることが
number of input parameters with affect the way that the method is called.
どのように、メソッドの呼ばれ方を変えるかを
Normally when you're building your app,
アプリを作るとき、
you will just define it one way with a certain number of input parameters.
普通は決まったインプット数を使いますが、
And usually that number of input parameters is going to be determined
そしてそのインプット数はメソッドの
based off of what's happening inside the method.
内容によって決まります。
The best practice is to only pass input parameters
メソッドで使うパラメータだけをインプットにするのが
that you're actually going to need inside this method.
最善の方法です。
There's no point in passing over more information if you're not going to
使う情報以上のものを渡しても
use it inside here.
意味がありませんよね。
Here are the instructions for this task.
この練習のためのガイドです。
First define the calculate price method in your app in the main activity.
まずmain activityのアプリでcalculatePriceメソッドを定義してください。
See the instrructor notes for a code snippet that you can start with.
指導書から使えるコードをコピーペイストしてください。
We're going to modify the calculatePrice method so
calculatePriceメソッドを変えて、インプットパラメータが
that it only has one input parameter.
一つになるようにします。
Then in the submitOrder method call calculatePrice and
submitOrderメソッドで、calculatePriceを呼んで、
pass in quantity as the input.
量をインプットとして渡します。
Then try to modify the calculatePrice method to have two input parameters.
次に、calculatePriceメソッドが二つのインプットを受け取るように 変更します。
That way in the submitOrder method you will call calculatePrice quantity and
submitOrderで
then you can pass in the price which could be $10 for example.
calculatePrice(quantity, 10)を呼んでみます
And lastly, try changing calculatePrice so that it has zero input parameters.
最後に、calculatePriceを変えて、インプットパラメータを無しにしてください
That way in the submitOrder method you would just call calculatePrice
submitOrderでは、calculatePriceとだけ呼びます。
like this.
こんな感じです。
Let's do the first one together so you understand what I mean.
最初のステップを一緒にやってみましょう。
I'm going to open up the link in the instructor notes.
指導書にあるリンクを開きます。
In this gist we provided code for the calculatePrice method.
GISTにcalculatePriceメソッドのコードを乗せました。
So go ahead and select everything and then copy it.
全てをコピーしてください。
In Android Studio, I'm going to paste in this method.
Android Studioにそれをペイストします。
I'm just going to paste it in right below submitOrder, and
submitOrderの下にペイストして、
I'll make sure that there's a blank line in between each method here.
一行空けておきます。
That makes it easier to read.
これで読みやすくなります。
Then I can call this method from the submitOrder method.
そしてsubmitOrderメソッドで、このメソッドを呼びます。
I'm just going to insert the call at the very bottom of the method.
メソッドを呼ぶのは一番下にしておきます。
Later we're going to integrate it with the code up here.
後にここのコードと統合します。
But for now, this is good.
今のところはこれで大丈夫でしょう。
Oops, I forgot that we have one input parameter, so I need a pass quantity.
一つインプリケーションパラメータを忘れていました。 量を渡さなければいけません。
Now do the same for
このインプットパラメータを変えて、
the remaining two tasks by modifying the input parameters here.
他の二つのエクササイズもやってみてください。
To complete this task, if you need examples to reference,
このエクササイズをやるうえで、参考がほしければ、
you can always do a Google search for Java methods.
JavaメソッドをGoogleで検索してもいいと思います。